PX-OS-002	interaction-assurance	assurance	interaction-assurance	backend	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The UI action inventory proves only rendered action names, declared prose contracts, and matching handler strings. It does not prove useful backend behavior, persistence, error handling, or live-host acknowledgement."	"Every visible action requires a behavior test through its real host boundary, authoritative state transition or read result, failure result, and visible acknowledgement."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-002"]}]
PX-OS-003	installed-extension	dashboard-control-plane	installed-extension	integration	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The live VS Code host was running an older extension than source and reported host-version-differs-from-source while certification work continued."	"The reloaded live host reports exact version, asset digest, asset protocol, and message schema equality."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-003"]}]
PX-OS-004	agent-builder	agent-studio	agent-builder	editor	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Agent Studio calls a long form a visual Builder. Its lifecycle strip is decorative; there is no selectable topology, connection model, node inspector, or visual composition of the agent runtime contract."	"A real canvas projects identity/start, behavior, harness/model route, capabilities/tools/skills/workflows, grants/scope, memory/context, tests/validation, approval, and terminal candidate nodes with inspectable typed connections."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-004"]}]
PX-OS-005	agent-builder	agent-studio	agent-builder	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Agent composition does not expose meaningful model-route, tool/skill/workflow selection, context/memory policy, output contract, or execution-preview relationships even though the surrounding product claims those systems exist."	"The builder may select only admitted metadata, visually distinguishes declarations from authority, round-trips all supported canonical fields, and previews the exact resolved execution contract without running it."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-005"]}]
PX-OS-006	agent-lifecycle	studio-lifecycle	agent-lifecycle	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The Agents surface emphasizes 270 source records while showing zero runnable revisions and zero processes; Studio lifecycle and run evidence are not the primary operational view."	"Candidate, tested, admitted, runnable, running, finalizing, completed, failed, and retired states are first-class, filterable, and linked to receipts and live controls."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-006"]}]
PX-OS-007	workflow-builder	workflow-studio	workflow-builder	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Workflow Studio is a primitive grid with three palette items and dropdown edge creation. It lacks direct port connection, useful node taxonomy, canvas navigation, automatic layout, execution trace overlay, and validation/approval visualization."	"Provide a usable pan/zoom canvas, typed handles, drag/keyboard composition, fit/layout, focused inspector, branching/approval/recovery nodes, validation overlays, and durable run trace projection."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-007"]}]
PX-OS-010	knowledge-graph-ui	knowledge-graph	knowledge-graph-ui	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The graph uses a large sparse canvas and a star-like neighborhood, leaving most space empty while labels, edge meaning, and structure remain difficult to read."	"Use adaptive hierarchical/force layouts, density-aware clustering, semantic color/shape, edge bundling or filtering, full-screen inspection, useful minimap, and responsive information density."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-010"]}]
PX-OS-013	provider-telemetry	runtime-core	provider-telemetry	runtime	medium	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Zero configured providers was displayed as Provider telemetry unavailable, conflating deliberate unconfigured state with failure."	"Live sidebar displays unconfigured when no provider is configured and unavailable only when a configured telemetry route fails."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-013"]}]
PX-OS-014	projects	projects	projects	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The Projects surface wastes most of the viewport on two summary panels and does not expose project-map freshness, rebuild history, repository modules, risks, services, routes, test links, or governed project operations."	"Turn the project surface into an operational project map and lifecycle view with dense current evidence, navigation, refresh/build actions, and precise authority boundaries."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-014"]}]
PX-OS-015	skills-tools	skills-tools	skills-tools	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Skills & Tools is mainly a catalog plus a static lifecycle strip. Skill creation/adaptation, preserved-original comparison, semantic broker selection, tests, admission, backup, promotion, and rollback are not first-class working flows."	"Expose package editing, original-versus-PX comparison, semantic routing rationale, domain isolation, test/admission state, provenance, backup, promotion, and rollback with real backend receipts."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-015"]}]
PX-OS-016	plugins	plugins	plugins	integration	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Plugin Manager is policy prose and inventory rows. It does not provide a complete governed discovery, compatibility, permission/effect review, install, update, enable/disable, uninstall, rollback, and conflict-resolution workflow."	"Each lifecycle operation is separately visible, approval-bound, reversible where possible, and verified against live host state."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-016"]}]
PX-OS-020	runtime-core	runtime-core	runtime-core	runtime	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Runtime Core is static identity prose and hardware totals. It does not expose scheduler queues, execution placement decisions, resource ownership, provider routes, GPU eligibility/fallback, process lifecycle, bottlenecks, or latency traces."	"Expose live bounded execution topology, placement rationale, CPU/GPU decisions, queue and worker state, owned resources/processes, provider routing, latency, failures, and recovery evidence."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-020"]}]
PX-OS-022	layout	dashboard-control-plane	layout	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Multiple surfaces allocate fixed-height panels to empty or disabled content, creating large dead regions while high-value live data is truncated, hidden below the fold, or relegated to modals."	"Empty sections collapse, content density adapts to available data, operational editors can use the full workspace, and no panel reserves space without useful content or action."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-022"]}]
PX-OS-023	completion-authority	assurance	completion-authority	backend	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Earlier completion and audit workflows did not treat these operational surface failures as blockers, allowing repeated certification work before the product worked correctly."	"This ledger is included in completion authority; no certification or certified naming is allowed while any critical/high operational finding is open or only fixture-verified."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-023"]}]
PX-OS-024	runtime-truth	runtime-core	runtime-truth	runtime	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Several health and authority labels were synthesized from bridge connectivity or hard-coded as operational even when the installed host identity differed from source and validation was not current."	"Every health label is derived from its own observed source and blockers; connection alone never upgrades identity, provider, memory, agent, workflow, validation, or extension status."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-024"]}]
PX-OS-025	agent-studio-persistence	agent-studio	agent-studio-persistence	editor	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Studio revisions can be persisted but are not reliably rediscovered or reopened after a webview reload because displayed catalogs are largely static and project-scoped revision discovery is incomplete."	"Created revisions appear in the catalog after reload with project identity, revision, status, source, and a working reopen/edit action."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-025"]}]
PX-OS-026	skill-package-resolution	skill-studio	skill-package-resolution	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Skill package resolution can ignore package_root and preserved-backup metadata, causing retained originals to open the wrong package or fail to hydrate."	"Current, enterprise, Microsoft, and preserved skill records resolve their declared package roots without crossing source boundaries."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-026"]}]
PX-OS-029	agent-runtime	runtime-core	agent-runtime	editor	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The current harness:px execution path is a deterministic local worker and does not invoke a declared AI model/provider route, while the surrounding Agent Studio presentation implied a complete agent runtime."	"The builder and runtime expose the exact model/provider route or clearly remain deterministic; execution contracts, results, and claims match the actual harness."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-029"]}]
PX-OS-030	lifecycle-controls	studio-lifecycle	lifecycle-controls	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Lifecycle dialogs offer next actions without evaluating prerequisites and omit truthful pause, resume, cancel, stop, reconcile, and rollback state where those operations are relevant."	"Only currently eligible operations are enabled, each names its authority and effects, and unsupported lifecycle operations are not presented as working controls."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-030"]}]
PX-OS-031	agent-execution	studio-lifecycle	agent-execution	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The agent run path uses a hard-coded objective instead of collecting and recording the user's actual bounded task and execution inputs."	"Run requires an explicit objective and shows the resolved agent revision, inputs, grants, provider/model or deterministic harness, stop conditions, and result record."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-031"]}]
PX-OS-032	cache-correctness	dashboard-control-plane	cache-correctness	backend	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Snapshot and validation cache fingerprints omit relevant runtime, extension, and Studio state, and directory fingerprints can ignore changed children, allowing stale passed state to survive material changes."	"All behavior-affecting sources participate in content-derived invalidation and stale validation can never be restored as current after relevant changes."	[{"path":"extension/src/pxBridge.js","symbols":["_sourceFingerprint","snapshot"]},{"path":"extension/tests/px-bridge-cache.test.js","symbols":["snapshot cache uses source fingerprints, TTL, and stale-while-revalidate"]}]
PX-OS-033	sidebar-routing	sidebar	sidebar-routing	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Sidebar deep links pass entity payloads that the dashboard ignores; providers route to a nonexistent governance surface and waves, orchestrations, providers, and attention records often open no usable detail."	"Every sidebar row routes to a real surface and opens the supplied current entity record or a specific not-found result."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-033"]}]
PX-OS-034	learning-promotion	knowledge-core	learning-promotion	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The evidence-to-promotion implementation is isolated from production controllers, CLI operations, and UI, so the displayed learning lifecycle is not an operating experience pipeline."	"Observed execution evidence can enter a governed candidate lifecycle with provenance, comparison, validation, promotion/decay decisions, and measured reuse."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-034"]}]
PX-OS-035	knowledge-integrity	knowledge-core	knowledge-integrity	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Knowledge UI language overstates independent verification, and directory identity can hash member names without hashing member contents while being presented as content identity."	"Verification wording matches performed checks and canonical hashes cover the exact governed content bytes represented by a revision."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-035"]}]
PX-OS-036	dashboard-controls	dashboard-control-plane	dashboard-controls	UI	medium	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Generic INSPECT controls repeat metric and panel text instead of drilling into evidence, consuming space without adding an operation."	"Generic controls are removed; any remaining inspect action opens specific provenance, history, source, or affected records."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-036"]}]
PX-OS-038	codex-handoff	runtime-core	codex-handoff	integration	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Continue/handoff can silently do nothing when the dashboard has not initialized and currently prepares a JSON context package rather than providing a seamless governed continuation."	"The action always acknowledges success/failure, initializes or blocks explicitly, and names the exact boundary between PX context preparation and Codex host execution authority."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-038"]}]
PX-OS-039	workflow-topology	workflow-studio	workflow-topology	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Workflow palette node types are cosmetic because persisted nodes do not retain typed kind/configuration and the canvas lacks inspectable typed ports and drawn connections."	"Node type and configuration round-trip to runtime semantics, edges render on the canvas with compatible ports, and invalid connections are blocked with a specific reason."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-039"]}]
PX-OS-040	repository-map-inputs	projects	repository-map-inputs	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Repository mapping included .venv-certify as project source, polluting the graph with third-party/generated files and obscuring the actual architecture."	"A live repository-map view shows the reduced current graph and future rebuilds retain the exclusion."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-040"]}]
PX-OS-041	sidebar-observability	sidebar	sidebar-observability	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Sidebar callback and outbound failures were caught as inbound schema rejections, producing misleading invalid-union diagnoses while Pacify-X output logs remained empty."	"Malformed messages, action failures, and outbound delivery failures retain distinct classifications in provider inspection and the live Pacify-X output log."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-041"]}]
PX-OS-042	async-ui-state	dashboard-control-plane	async-ui-state	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"A stale graph, catalog, memory, or activity operationError could overwrite a newer successful request because failure handling ignored request identity."	"Out-of-order success and failure responses affect only the matching active request."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-042"]}]
PX-OS-043	studio-draft-custody	studio-lifecycle	studio-draft-custody	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Saving a Studio draft closed the editor before host approval, so canceling approval left the unsaved draft inaccessible."	"Canceling any pre-create host prompt leaves every draft field accessible and unchanged."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-043"]}]
PX-OS-044	settings-mcp	settings	settings-mcp	backend	medium	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Settings read snapshot.mcp even though the host publishes snapshot.observability.mcp, causing false unavailable status."	"Settings MCP state matches the same host observation shown by diagnostics."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-044"]}]
PX-OS-045	memory-truth	memory	memory-truth	persistence	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The service grid labeled canonical memory Attached from instrumentation presence rather than lease-bound retrieval readiness."	"Attached is shown only while canonical retrieval is configured, valid, registered, leased, and ready."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-045"]}]
PX-OS-046	enterprise-readiness	assurance	enterprise-readiness	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Enterprise panels hard-coded local control plane ready before a doctor result and even after failed checks."	"Readiness wording and tone always match the current doctor report while connectors remain disabled."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-046"]}]
PX-OS-047	skill-studio-identity	skill-studio	skill-studio-identity	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Skill Studio identity/version fields did not update capability.json, skill.yaml, or SKILL.md, allowing apparently valid but internally split candidates."	"Changing identity or version produces one internally consistent native skill package or a specific blocking error."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-047"]}]
PX-OS-048	agent-session-freshness	activity	agent-session-freshness	editor	medium	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Agent active-session metrics counted ledger status without heartbeat freshness, allowing stale sessions to look active."	"Expired or missing heartbeats never contribute to active-session counts."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-048"]}]
PX-OS-049	requirements-authority	assurance	requirements-authority	UI	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"No single current ledger maps every user instruction, supplied audit, architecture add-on, punch card, implementation owner, runtime owner, and live acceptance result. Work repeatedly followed the newest report while earlier requirements silently disappeared."	"Maintain one dependency-ordered instruction ledger with a stable requirement ID, source, owner, implementation state, live state, contrary evidence, and blocking finding IDs for every requested outcome."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-049"]}]
PX-OS-050	completion-projection	assurance	completion-projection	backend	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"registry/completion_status.json is stale and internally contradictory: it reports cards_complete=true and 81/81 historical cards accepted, describes only 23 operational findings, and carries source hashes that no longer match the current operational ledger and punch-card document."	"Completion projections derive from the current operational ledger, distinguish historical acceptance from present state, verify every source digest, and cannot report cards complete while any current critical/high finding is open or pending live verification."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-050"]}]
PX-OS-051	codex-startup	runtime-core	codex-startup	runtime	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The original long Codex startup question was answered with PX extension activation time, which measures the wrong boundary. Current host evidence shows eager VS Code extensions, Python/Pylance discovery, a 4-5 second Copilot activation blocker, a Node REPL MCP with a 120-second startup allowance, and multiple per-agent node_repl processes; the Codex code-mode host appeared roughly 94 seconds after the extension host restart."	"Trace VS Code launch, ChatGPT extension activation, Codex app-server readiness, MCP readiness, skill discovery, and first usable tool separately; make optional MCP/plugin work lazy or explicitly bounded and retain a current end-to-end cold/warm readiness report."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-051"]}]
PX-OS-052	skill-host-boundary	skills-tools	skill-host-boundary	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The project has 16 concise PX facades, but Codex still discovers global Microsoft/Foundry skills directly from the user .agents tree. PX domain policy applies only when the facade broker is used and cannot prevent host-level direct selection, so the requested no-bleed boundary is advisory rather than enforced."	"Define an enforceable host-compatible loading boundary or a truthful limitation: project work defaults to facade-only semantic selection, vendor/enterprise bodies require explicit intent and grants, and direct global discovery cannot be presented as PX-isolated."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-052"]}]
PX-OS-053	skill-index-integrity	skills-tools	skill-index-integrity	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The native skill index contains 177 px-standard records but its declared counts report 176. Adding the execution-placement skill updated records and the index revision without updating the denominator, allowing dashboard and lifecycle projections to disagree."	"Every skill-index mutation atomically regenerates records, domain counts, revision, package projection, and catalog views from the same record set and refuses publication on denominator drift."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-053"]}]
PX-OS-054	runtime-efficiency-architecture	runtime-core	runtime-efficiency-architecture	runtime	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"A JavaScript WorkGovernor covers selected extension bridge operations, but the supplied architecture's canonical Event Hub, cross-runtime dependency/revision graph, State Bus, shared telemetry sampler, causal invalidation, incremental validation owner, adaptive idle governance, and single admission path for all expensive Python/extension work are not implemented as one operating system."	"Trace every expensive producer to one bounded admission owner, publish causal revisions and deltas through a canonical state bus, prove stable idle becomes quiet, and expose why work ran, joined, invalidated, waited, or fell back."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-054"]}]
PX-OS-055	execution-placement	runtime-core	execution-placement	runtime	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The supplied execution-placement add-on was reduced to side-effect-free CLI scoring. It is not connected to the live scheduler, Runtime Core, benchmark owner, rollback workflow, or UI; it implements promotion tiers only through 3 and does not produce the add-on's required Tier 4/5 production/reusable-pattern lifecycle or complete boundary/benchmark/rollback artifact set."	"Integrate keep-current decisions with observed workloads, matched before/after benchmarks, boundary contracts, partial-unit promotion, rollback, Runtime Core telemetry, and all defined promotion tiers without authorizing migration from the scorer alone."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-055"]}]
PX-OS-056	workflow-semantics	workflow-studio	workflow-semantics	editor	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Workflow Studio persists and signs task, validation, and approval node kinds plus node configuration, but workflow_worker.py ignores node_kind and node_config and dispatches only five hardcoded adapters. Validation nodes perform no validation behavior and arbitrary node configuration has no runtime effect."	"Every visible node kind has an explicit executable contract and result schema, unsupported kinds/configuration are blocked before save, and the run trace proves the exact configured semantics rather than a cosmetic label."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-056"]}]
PX-OS-057	workflow-scheduling	workflows	workflow-scheduling	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Workflow execution iterates one topological order serially; independent ready branches never run concurrently even when their claims and dependencies permit it. This contradicts the requested bounded parallel execution and makes visually parallel workflows misleading and slow."	"Schedule ready nodes through bounded claim-safe pools, preserve deterministic joins and failure policy, expose queue/worker timing, and retain a serial fallback for conflicts or unsafe effects."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-057"]}]
PX-OS-058	studio-run-lifecycle	studio-lifecycle	studio-run-lifecycle	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The backend exposes status, pause, cancel, stop, resume, and reconcile, but Studio has no durable run monitor or controls for those operations. Multiple approval nodes are also mishandled because the UI offers Run after the first approval rather than the next required approval."	"Provide a durable session/run browser with only eligible lifecycle actions, exact approval progression for every node, live/finalizing/terminal traces, reconciliation, and visible acknowledgements."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-058"]}]
PX-OS-059	agent-testing	studio-lifecycle	agent-testing	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Agent Studio labels free-text IDs as required certification tests, but the runtime implements only identity and sandbox checks and rejects every other ID. There is no test authoring, scenario/fixture binding, capability-specific validation, section gate, or result explorer."	"Rename the current checks truthfully or implement typed admitted test definitions, scenario inputs, expected outcomes, evidence, and inspectable results; arbitrary text must not imply executable certification."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-059"]}]
PX-OS-060	copilot-integration	plugins	copilot-integration	integration	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Pacify-X contributes a local language-model provider and an MCP definition but no Copilot chat participant or end-to-end Codex/Copilot session correlation. It prepares a portable JSON context document and explicitly cannot continue, observe, or govern the active chat execution seamlessly."	"Use supported host APIs to provide explicit governed context/session correlation and acknowledgement; where host APIs cannot transfer or control a chat, state that boundary plainly and never call the JSON handoff seamless integration."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-060"]}]
PX-OS-061	studio-transactionality	studio-lifecycle	studio-transactionality	persistence	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Agent/workflow creation writes the immutable revision before authority-definition.json. If authority validation or sidecar publication fails, a partial revision remains even though the host reports save failure."	"Publish revision, authority definition, index/catalog projection, and receipt through one recoverable transaction or leave no discoverable revision; restart reconciliation must resolve every prepared/partial state."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-061"]}]
PX-OS-062	css-ownership	dashboard-control-plane	css-ownership	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Layered modular styles are followed by a large unlayered legacy dashboard.css that redefines topbar, graph, modal, and component selectors. The later sheet constrains Studio width, repeatedly changes graph node size, and leaves the promotion ladder without safe overflow, matching the observed collisions and clipping."	"Establish one CSS ownership/layer order, remove conflicting duplicate selectors, allow editors to use the available viewport, and make topbar, graph, lifecycle, and promotion surfaces responsive without clipping or hidden controls."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-062"]}]
PX-OS-063	sidebar-subtasks	sidebar	sidebar-subtasks	UI	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Sidebar subtask buttons emit the parent task ID and the provider indexes only top-level tasks, so selecting a subtask opens the parent or produces an unavailable record."	"Index and route each subtask by its own stable identity and prove the selected sidebar record, dashboard deep link, and backend evidence refer to the same entity."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-063"]}]
PX-OS-064	health-taxonomy	diagnostics	health-taxonomy	backend	critical	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The dashboard makes operational health depend on a current passed validation receipt, conflating connectivity and functional availability with certification freshness. This drives the same validation-first behavior the user explicitly rejected."	"Project independent dimensions for host identity, runtime connectivity, feature availability, degraded faults, evidence freshness, and certification state; stale certification must not make a working runtime non-operational or trigger certification as the default repair."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-064"]}]
PX-OS-065	storage-retention	runtime-core	storage-retention	persistence	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Storage rules are not closed operationally. The current tree contains about 0.88 GiB of project-map current/history data, nearly 12,000 operation-bus files, multiple retained extension generations, and 1,373 Git status entries; historical cleanup receipts cannot prove current retention, incremental compaction, or disk behavior."	"Classify current ownership/retention, keep authoritative and user-owned evidence recoverable, compact or archive only PX-owned expired ephemerals through the safe reclamation gate, and expose current size/growth/last-cleanup evidence without treating Git dirtiness as a fault."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-065"]}]
PX-OS-066	skill-first-initialization	skills-tools	skill-first-initialization	editor	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"The first skill migration copies one verified workspace snapshot, builds packages, then moves the original .agents/skills tree before publishing final custody state. A change or interruption between copy and move can leave a partially migrated tree; the move is not one recoverable transaction and does not perform the required immediate pre-move equality check."	"Use two matching full-tree snapshots plus immediate pre-move equality, a recoverable transaction journal, idempotent restart reconciliation, immutable original and verified backup custody, and incremental add/adapt behavior after initialization."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-066"]}]
PX-OS-067	incremental-test-governance	diagnostics	incremental-test-governance	backend	high	"historical finding; exact visible action must be reconciled"	"Section/group and run-stale mechanisms exist, but the current completion projection reports eight stale or failed required receipts and no live evidence proves that unchanged restarts avoid broad work or that only affected groups rerun after change. Historical accepted cards cannot close the requested first-initialization-then-incremental behavior."	"Keep certification paused, expose affected-section selection and dependency reasons, prove unchanged state performs no section work, rerun only stale dependency closures during repair, and reserve one full profile for an explicitly resumed final trust transition."	[{"path":"registry/operational_surface_audit_20260816.json","symbols":["PX-OS-067"]}]
